Contact

San Diego, CA 92122 949-466-2546 (Mobile) alisarkeshik@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/alisarkeshik (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

JavaScript jQuery HTML

Publications

https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/ pubmed?term=sarkeshik (Search for Sarkeshik)

Ali Sarkeshik

Full Stack Developer at UC San Diego Extension San Diego, California

Summary

Solutions-driven Full Stack Developer/Software Engineer who uses ingenuity and creativity to build fluid and functional web applications. My previous experience includes method development in Chemistry and Instrumentation (hardware and software troubleshooting) in a resale and OEM environment.

Experience

UC San Diego Extension Full Stack Developer February 2019 - Present Greater San Diego Area

For a list of my coding projects please visit: https://alisarkeshik.github.io/UpdatedPortfolio/portfolio.html

Learning front-end and back-end technologies through a dynamic curriculum:

Database Theory, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Java, MongoDB, MySQL, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Bookshelf.js, AJAX, Firebase Command Line, and Git

PerkinElmer, Inc.
Customer Support Engineer
June 2018 - December 2018 (7 months)
Greater San Diego Area

- Provide on-site personalized support services for PerkinElmer instruments
- Provide troubleshooting expertise and repair skills needed to help identify and resolve issues related to hardware, software or applications support.
- -Performed PMs, installs, and repairs on various Perkin Elmer instruments (Janus, LabChip, SciClone, Zephyr, and Euroimmune products).

Roche Diagnostics
Planned Activities Specialist/Field Service Engineer
January 2018 - May 2018 (5 months)

Page 1 of 3

Greater San Diego Area (Contract position via Tailored Management)

- -Performed on-site preventative maintenance, installation, and technical updates (TSB's) on company products (Cobas 6000 and 8000 analyzers).
- -Diagnosed mechanical, hardware, software and system failures
- -Trained in: CD Foundations of Hardware, IT Products, c6000/8000 Service Operator Training, and Cobas 6000 Install/Core Service

BioSurplus, Inc.
Service Engineer
January 2017 - July 2017 (7 months)
Greater San Diego Area

- -Determined the re-sale viability of company acquisitions.
- -Diagnosed, repaired, and serviced a wide range of laboratory equipment.
- -Systems included but were not limited to: Flow Cytometry (BD FacsCalibur, Luminex 100 and 200), Centrifuges (Beckman Coulter, Sorvall, Eppendorf), Refrigeration systems (Cold Freezers and Incubators), Automated Liquid Handlers (Tecan Evo Freedom), Mass Spectrometry (Agilent, Shimadzu, Thermo), HPLC (Agilent 1100/1200), and GC (Agilent 6850/6890).

Versum Materials (Formerly known as Air Products and Chemicals, Inc.)

Analytical Chemist

November 2013 - January 2017 (3 years 3 months)

Carlsbad, CA (Contract Position via The Fountain Group: November 2013 – May 2015

- -Worked closely with a team of researchers to support method development for new products.
- -Performed hands on installation (hardware/software), calibrations, troubleshooting, and maintenance on GC instruments (Agilent 5973/6850/6890/Thermo Trace 1310).
- -GC-TCD/GC-FID, GC-MS, DIP-MS analysis of organo silanes and GC-PHID analysis of Octane
- -Successfully assisted in transitioning R&D products to commercial status (ISO: 9001:2008, 17025, 10012)

BP

Research Associate
March 2013 - October 2013 (8 months)

Greater San Diego Area (Contract Position via Collabera)

- -SEC-HPLC Analysis of: Organic Acids, Sugars, Oligomers, Solids, and Furans in Fermentation and Yeast engineering Samples
- -IC Analysis of Organic Acids
- -Headspace GC Analysis and Method Development of Ethanol, Isobutanol, Isobutyl Acetate, and Ethyl Acetate in Fermentation Samples

Ionis Pharmaceuticals (Formerly ISIS Pharmaceuticals)
Research Associate/Scientist - Oligo Synthesis
October 2012 - November 2012 (2 months)

Carlsbad, CA (Contract position via Aerotek)

- -Production of synthetic oligonucleotides (using Mermade 192 synthesizer) in a GLP environment
- -Analytical techniques used: C5 and C8 SAX purification (GE AKTA Explorer) and C7 Desalt (GE AKTA Avant)
- -Utilized Agilent 6130 Quadrople LC-MS to verify fraction purity

The Scripps Research Institute
Research Technician
July 2006 - July 2011 (5 years 1 month)
La Jolla, CA

- -Performed hands installation (hardware/software), calibration, troubleshooting, and preventative maintenance on LC/LC-MS (LTQ and LTQ Orbitrap) and HPLC instruments (Agilent 1100)
- -Protein characterization and data analysis by Mass Spectrometry (MS) of over 1000 protein complexes (Using Agilent 1100 RP-HPLC, LTQ and LTQ Orbitrap)
- -Technical editing and writing experience: successful construction and implementation of new YRC SOPs, co-authoring scientific publications, creation and maintenance of YRC protocol and instrumentation webpage
- -Database maintenance, creation, and modification for YRC Public Data Repository
- -Successfully improved YRC data processing system (Data submission, database parsing, etc)

Education

University of California, Riverside Chemistry, Bachelor of Science